The extraordinary adaptation of Shakespeare's
classic tale of vengeance and tragedy.
Hamlet is a drama, history film directed by Franco Zeffirelli.
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark, finds out that his uncle Claudius killed
his father to obtain the throne, and plans revenge.
Hamlet, played by Mel Gibson.
Gertrude, played by Glenn Close.
Claudius, played by Alan Bates.
The Ghost, played by Paul Scofield.
Polonius, played by Ian Holm.
Ophelia, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Hamlet is a 1990 drama film based on the Shakespearean tragedy of the same name, directed
by Franco Zeffirelli and starring Mel Gibson as the eponymous character.
The film also features Glenn Close, Alan Bates, Paul Scofield, Ian Holm,
Helena Bonham Carter, Stephen Dillane, and Nathaniel Parker.
An international co-production between the United States, the United Kingdom, Italy and France, the
film was the first produced by Icon Productions, a company co-founded by Gibson.
The film explores themes of loss of loved one, prince,
uncle, based on play or musical, revenge.
The tone is emotional.